Guide to the Scottie Fitzgerald Smith Papers, 1858-1996 (bulk 1921-1986)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series V. Writings
  - "News to Me" column, Washington Post, 1966-1967; (2 folders - original clippings) (Folders 5.1 - 5.2)
  - "News to Me" column, Washington Post, 1966-1967; (photocopies) (Folder 5.3)
  - "News to Me" column, Washington Post, circa 1966-1967; (typescript drafts) (Folder 5.4)
  - "Centers are Up Their Alley," Washington Post, Feb 1967 (Folder 5.5)
  - "The Group and I," McCall's, July 1967; (clipping) (Folder 3.25)
  - "The Group and I," McCall's, July 1967; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "Happy New Year: 5728," Washington Post, 3 Oct 1967 (Folder 3.26)
  - Unpublished "News to Me" piece, Nov 1967 (Folder 3.27)
  - "Christmas Radiance at the White House, House and Garden, Dec 1967; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "The Alternative Prospect," Letter to the editor of The Washington Post, 17 Sep 1968 (Folder 3.28)
  - Advertisements for "United Democrats for Humphrey,", 1968; (end of both scrapbook albums) (Boxes 27-28)
  - "The Sugar Tiger of Georgetown," Washingtonian, with Winzola McLendon, May 1969 (Folder 3.29)
  - Novel about Washington, circa 1969; (2 folders) (Folders 5.6 - 5.7)
  - Don't Quote Me — Early drafts and correspondence, circa 1969 (Folder 3.30)
  - Don't Quote Me — Drafts of various chapters, circa 1969 (Folder 3.31)
  - Don't Quote Me — "Autobiographical Resume,", circa 1969 (Folder 3.32)
  - Don't Quote Me — Rights and royalties, 1969-1974 (Folder 5.8)
  - Don't Quote Me — Clippings, 1970 (Folder 5.9)
  - Excerpt from Don't Quote Me, Ladies Home Journal, Nov 1970; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "How Washington Women Stay Young," Washingtonian, with Winzola McLendon, Apr 1970 (Folder 3.33)
  - "The Art of Gossip," Sunday Herald Tribune, 22 Nov 1970 (Folder 5.10)
  - "Georgetown: The Living End," Venture, with Winzola McLendon, Dec-Jan 1970 (Folder 3.34)
  - "Recipe for a Washington Dinner Party," Ladies Home Journal, with Winzola McLendon, May 1971; (clipping) (Folder 3.35)
  - "Recipe for a Washington Dinner Party," Ladies Home Journal, with Winzola McLendon, May 1971; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - "The Round Trip" — Movie outline by FSFLS and Winzola McLendon, circa 1972 (Folder 3.36)
  - "Four Christmas Memories," Washington Post Potomac, 23 Dec 1973 (Folder 6.2)
  - Bits of Paradise — Preface, 1973 (Folder 5.11)
  - Bits of Paradise — Scrapbook of photocopied clippings, 1974; (final pages of scrapbook) (Box 29 (Oversize))
  - "Farewell Address... to Washington,", circa 1973 (Folder 3.37)
  - "Notes About My Now Famous Father," Family Circle, May 1974 (Folder 3.38)
  - The Romantic Egoists — General, 1974-1975, undated (Folder 5.12)
  - The Romantic Egoists — Clippings, 1974-1975 (Folder 5.13)
  - The Romantic Egoists — Scrapbook of clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 29 (Oversize))
  - Introduction for Susan Mary Jay Patten, 23 Oct 1975 (Folder 3.39)
  - An Alabama Journal, 1976 (Folder 5.14)
  - "Dede Goodhue: At Home in the Chamber," Vassar Quarterly, 1977 (Folder 3.40)
  - "The Colonial Ancestors of Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald,", 1981 (Folder 3.41)
  - Outline for Novel by Dot Moore, Jack Wagnon and FSFLS, circa 1982 (Folder 3.42)
  - "The Maryland Ancestors of Zelda Sayre Fitzgerald,", 1983 (Folder 3.43)
  - "Ferraro: Two Views," Montgomery Advertiser, 26 Oct 1984 (Folder 3.44)
  - "The Big Benefit," with Mary Channing, undated (Folder 3.45)
  - "The Compliment,", undated (Folder 3.46)
  - "Gin and Diapers,", undated (Folder 3.47)
  - "Lesson One,", undated (Folder 5.15)
  - "Life in Our Hick Town, London Sunday Times, undated (Folder 3.48)
  - "A Matter of Time" by Victoria Mims [pen name or Sayre family member?], undated (Folder 3.49)
  - "The New Washington Society: Is it for Real," with Winzola McLendon, undated (Folder 3.50)
  - "Novel,", undated; (notebook) (Folder 3.51)
  - "Panel Discussion,", undated (Folder 3.52)
  - "The Tale of Herbert Rabbit: A Cocktail-Time Story,", undated (Folder 3.53)
  - "We Wives,", undated (Folder 3.54)
  - Unpublished piece for the New York Sunday Times, undated (Folder 3.55)
  - Unpublished piece for the New York Sunday Times, undated (Folder 3.56)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 3.57)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 5.16)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Folder 5.17)
- Series VI. F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald
  - F. Scott Fitzgerald
    - Will, 1937 (Folder 5.18)
    - Estate (John Biggs), 1943-1946 (Folder 5.19)
    - Clippings, 1945-1989; (3 folders) (Folders 5.20 - 5.22)
    - "The Spell of Scott Fitzgerald Grows Stronger," Life, 16 Feb 1959; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous rights issues, 1955-1974 (Folder 5.23)
    - Papers at Princeton University, 1956-1975 (Folder 3.58)
    - Tender is the Night — Selznick film adaptation, 1960 (Folder 3.59)
    - The Great Gatsby — Aubrey Goodman musical, 1961 (Folder 3.60)
    - The Great Gatsby — Artie Shaw musical, 1969-1978 (Folder 5.24)
    - The Great Gatsby — Film —Rights and royalties, 1961, 1971-1973 (Folder 5.25)
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald: A Definitive Bibliography, 1972 (Folder 3.61)
    - The Great Gatsby — Film — FSFLS's notes on the screenplay, 1973 (Folder 3.62)
    - The Great Gatsby — Film — Release party, 1974 (Folder 5.26)
    - The Great Gatsby — Film — Clippings, 1974 (Folder 5.27)
    - The Great Gatsby — Film — Clippings, 1974 (Folder 6.4)
    - The Great Gatsby — Film — Clippings —Sunday Times and Vogue, 1974; (complete magazines) (Box 6)
    - "The F. Scott Fitzgerald Follies," University Club of Saint Paul, 1975 (Folder 3.63)
    - The Last Tycoon — Film —Rights and royalties, 1975-1976 (Folder 5.28)
    - Three Comrades screenplay — Publication, 1978 (Folder 3.64)
    - Tender is the Night — Foreign editions, circa 1980 (Folder 5.29)
    - University of Minnesota Conference, 1982 (Folder 3.65)
    - The Great Gatsby — Arion Press edition, 1985 (Folder 3.66)
    - Sale of 1939 letter from FSF to FSFLS, 1985 (Folder 5.30)
    - Matthew Bruccoli's lecture guides, 1988 (Folder 3.67)
    - St Paul coloring book featuring FSF, produced by the Gaultier Plaza, circa 1980s (Folder 6.3)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 5.31)
    - Garrison Keillor's "A Prairie Home Companion" radio show, recorded at the St. Paul Minnesota's Fitzgerald Theater, renamed the previous week for F. Scott Fitzgerald. Keillor described the events surrounding the rededication and played a University of Michigan tape of F. Scott reading Keats' Ode to a Nightingale, 1 Oct 1994; (51:12 - first 15 minutes are about Fitzgerald) (Box 11 - CD 68 (Tape 12))
    - Fitzgerald Society, Princeton University Centennial Conference — Honoria Murphy Donnelly, introduced by Linda P. Miller, September 1996; (Track 1, 32:47 - poor recording) (Box 12 - CD 69 (Tape 48))
    - Fitzgerald Society, Princeton University Centennial Conference — Fanny Myers Brennan on her life, including her childhood in Paris, September 1996; (Track 2, 29:34 - poor recording) (Box 12 - CD 69 (Tape 48))
    - Fitzgerald Society, Princeton University Centennial Conference — Budd Schulberg and Frances Kroll Ring, September 1996; (32:37) (Box 12 - CD 70 (Tape 49))
    - Fitzgerald Society, Princeton University Centennial Conference —Ring Lardner Jr. and Tony Butitta, September 1996; (31:50) (Box 12 - CD 71 (Tape 49))
    - Fitzgerald Society, Princeton University Centennial Conference —[George Garrett?], September 1996; (32:35 and 6:40) (Box 12 - CD 72 (Tape 50))
  - Zelda Fitzgerald
    - Clippings, 1948-1987 (Folder 5.32)
    - Nancy Milford biography, 1963-1970 (Folder 3.68)
    - Save Me the Waltz— Film idea by Jerome Hellman, 1971-1973 (Folder 5.33)
    - Papers at Princeton University, 1972 (Folder 3.69)
    - Article about Zelda's paper dolls, Mademoiselle, Mar 1974 (Folder 3.70)
    - Art Patron League of Mobile Exhibition, 1975; (2 folders) (Folders 5.34 - 5.35)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1986 (Folder 3.71)
    - Unidentified pair of bead-woven shoes — [made by Zelda?], undated (Box 26)
  - F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald
    - Memorial Park, Montgomery, Alabama, 1971 (Folder 5.36)
    - Re-interment, 1974-1975 (Folder 5.37)
    - Re-interment — Clippings, 1975 (Folder 5.38)
    - Re-interment — Clippings, 1975 (Folder 6.5)
    - Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald Museum Association, Montgomery, Alabama, 1987-1988, undated (Folder 3.72)
    - Homes (Folder 5.39)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 5.40)
- Series VII. Political Activity and Interests
  - Scrapbook — Politics, 1956 (Box 17)
  - Democratic National Convention and Tour, 1956 (Folder 7.1)
  - Democratic National Committee — Caravan, 1964; (2 folders) (Folders 7.2 - 7.3)
  - Democratic National Committee — Race, 1964 (Folder 7.4)
  - Humphrey/Muskie Campaign, 1968 (Folder 7.5)
  - Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, circa 1970 (Folder 7.6)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1972 (Folder 7.7)
  - McGovern Campaign, 1971-1972 (Folder 7.8)
  - "Notes on the McGovern Campaign for Teddy White's Book,", 1972; (2 drafts and a letter to and from Theodore H. White) (Folder 7.9)
  - Participants in the "Grassroots Grasshopper" train tour for the George McGovern campaign talking about their experiences. Speakers included: Liz Carpenter, "Ethel," "Fred" (photographer), FSFLS, C. Grove Smith, Liz Carrie, "Penny," "Judy," Cecilia Lanahan, and several unidentified people, 25 October 1972; (25:52) (Box 10 - CD 73 (Reel 2))
  - Hyman, Lester and Helen — the running of the George McGovern Campaign (Interviewed by FSFLS and C. Grove Smith), 1972; (64:04) (Box 10 - CD 74 (Reel 3))
  - Hyman, Lester and Helen — the running of the George McGovern Campaign (Interviewed by FSFLS and C. Grove Smith), 1972; (27:43) (Box 10 - CD 75 (Reel 3))
  - Hyman, Lester and Helen — the running of the George McGovern Campaign (Interviewed by FSFLS and C. Grove Smith), 1972; (47:17) (Box 10 - CD 76 (Reel 4))
  - Montgomery, Alabama, circa 1978-1979 (Folder 7.10)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1980 (Folder 7.11)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1954-1979, undated (Folder 7.12)
  - Ephemera (Folder 7.13)
  - News clippings about race, women's rights, and other issues (Folder 7.14)
  - Badges, pins and other realia — includes a parade official ribbon from the JFK/LBJ Inaugural Parade and 2 Adlai Stevenson buttons (Box 26)
- Series VIII. Musical Theater and Skits
  - Vassar College, circa 1938-1985 (Folder 8.1)
  - Vassar College - copy of OMGIM group's songs, circa 1940s; (8:36) (Box 12 - CD 77 (Tape 51))
  - Scrapbook — Mostly MS skits, 1953-1956 (Box 16)
  - MS programs, 1954-1967 (Folder 8.2)
  - Clippings, 1955-1959; (2 folders) (Folders 8.3 - 8.4)
  - "Jolly's Folly,", 1957; (2 folders) (Folders 8.5 - 8.6)
  - "See How They Run,", 1960 (Folder 8.7)
  - "See How They Run" MS show performance, 1960; (30:37) (Box 10 - CD 82 (Reel 5))
  - "See How They Run" MS show performance, 1960; (31:16) (Box 10 - CD 83 (Reel 6))
  - "See How They Run" MS show performance, 1960; (14:10) (Box 10 - CD 84 (Reel 7))
  - "See How They Run" professional recording, undated; (26:14) (Box 10 - CD 85 (Reel 8))
  - "New Front Here,", 1961 (Folder 8.8)
  - "New Front Here" MS show performance, 1961; (29:01) (Box 10 - CD 86 (Reel 9))
  - "New Front Here" MS show performance, 1961; (29:26) (Box 10 - CD 87 (Reel 10))
  - Untitled production — "First NY efforts...", 1961 (Folder 8.9)
  - Pros singing - "1st N.Y. effort,", [1961]; (Track 1 - minutes 1-14 and 29-35) (Box 10 - CD 94 (Reel 17))
  - International Ball script, 1962 (Folder 8.10)
  - "How to Succeed in Washington by Really Trying,", 1962 (Folder 8.11)
  - "How to Succeed" MS show performance, 1962; (29:05) (Box 10 - CD 88 (Reel 11))
  - Washington Festival of Performing Cultures, 1963 (Folder 8.12)
  - "Washington Festival of Performing Cultures," MS show performance, 1963; (29:55) (Box 10 - CD 89 (Reel 12))
  - "Washington Festival of Performing Cultures," MS show performance, 1963; (31:49) (Box 10 - CD 90 (Reel 13))
  - "Onward and Upward,", circa 1963; (5 folders) (Folders 8.13 -8.17)
  - "Onward and Upward,", [1963?]; (24:21) (Box 10 - CD 91 (Reel 14))
  - "Onward and Upward,", [1963?]; (46:14) (Box 10 - CD 92 (Reel 15))
  - "Stop the Press,", 1966 (Folder 8.18)
  - "Playing Politics,", undated; (26:12) (Box 10 - CD 93 (Reel 16))
  - Recording of FSFLS's songs, recorded at reception for "Cat's Whiskers," Auburn University, October 1988; (11:01) (Box 12 - CD 78 (Tape 52))
  - Miscellaneous sheet music (Folder 8.19)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 8.20)
- Series IX. Photographs
  - Family album, 1920-1985 (Boxes 20-21)
  - Photocopies of family album in original order with annotations (Box 20)
  - Vassar album, circa 1938-1942 (Box 19)
  - Wedding album, 1942 (Box 17)
  - Album of MS productions, 1956-1962 (Box 19)
  - Loose photos and photos removed from other parts of the collection, circa 1921-1985 (Box 22)
  - Anthony D. Sayre, undated (Folder 23.4)
  - Calvert School graduation, circa 1933 (Folder 23.5)
  - Mary Janney, Frances Kilpatrick and Mary Earle — Vassar production of "Guess Who's Here,", 1940 (Folder 23.6)
  - Life Magazine photos of FSFLS and her children, 1959, 1960; (2 photographs) (Folder 23.7)
- Series X. Miscellaneous
  - Green Acres School, circa 1951-1954 (Folder 3.73)
  - Publications with unidentified connections to FSFLS (Folder 3.74)
  - Publications with unidentified connections to FSFLS (Box 6)
  - Clippings — Betty Beale (Folder 5.41)
  - Clippings — Martha Mitchell (Folder 5.42)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Folder 5.43)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 3.75)
  - Reproduction of Charles Pinet etching of Notre Dame, inscribed by [Christiane Johnson], 29 Aug 1973 (Folder 23.9)
  - Smithsonian Tour of a Louisiana historic sites along the Mississippi with Ceci Carusi — Rosedown Plantation, [Fall 1973?]; (minutes 23-47) (Box 11 - CD 7 (Tape 3 side b))
  - Smithsonian Tour of a Louisiana historic sites along the Mississippi with Ceci Carusi — unidentified site, [Fall 1973?]; (46:50) (Box 12 - CD 79 (Tape 53 side a))
  - Smithsonian Tour of a Louisiana historic sites along the Mississippi with Ceci Carusi — Shadows-on-the-Teche and 2 unidentified sites, [Fall 1973?]; (minutes 1-27 and 31-35) (Box 12 - CD 80 (Tape 53 side b))
  - Smithsonian Tour of a Louisiana historic sites along the Mississippi with Ceci Carusi — FSFLS and Ceci talking about what they learned on their tours and how an article might be written, [Fall 1973?]; (minutes 27-31 and 35-40) (Box 12 - CD 80 (Tape 53 side b))
  - Malloy, Wilda and Virginia Durr — discuss the history and genealogy of Bullock and Montgomery Counties, Alabama (Interviewed by FSFLS ), undated; (31:04 and 29:24) (Box 12 - CD 81 (Tape 54))
  - Samuel Jackson "Jacky" Lanahan presentation on emergency response in Oregon, undated; (minutes 36-46) (Box 11 - CD 2 (Tape 1 side a))
  - Unidentified presentation on gardening, undated; (minutes 19-31 of track 2 ) (Box 12 - CD 53 (Tape 36))
  - Pop music from the radio, circa 1960s; (Track 1 - minutes 14-29) (Box 10 - CD 94 (Reel 17))
  - Lanahan daughters playing with the recorder, circa 1960s; (Track 2 - 13:30) (Box 10 - CD 94 (Reel 17))
- Series XI. Unprocessed Additions
  - Correspondence, papers, 1957-1979 (Folder 8.21)